<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Door Coworking</title>
    <description>Open Door Coworking is LaPorte, Indiana&#39;s first coworking space for freelancers, entrepreneurs, and telecommuters to call home. Work independently; not alone.</description>
    <link>https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 11:00:29 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 11:00:29 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>6 Reasons to Leave the Home Office Behind</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I know what you’re thinking… “My home office is just fine.  There’s no reason that I should join a coworking space,” and you may be right, but imagine for a second what life might be outside of the house.  Really reflect on your current situation and ask yourself if you’re really as productive as you could be while working in your underwear 50 paces from your bed.  Having a hard time picturing it?  No problem!  That’s what this post is all about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;list-header&quot;&gt; 1. Distractions &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Distractions ruin productivity, and you and I both know that in the age we live in, disctractions are everywhere.  Your phone beeps, your watch buzzes, your computer dings, and sometimes they all happen at the same time.  These are all part of the cost of being connected, and are sometimes unavoidable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;float-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;He&#39;s cute, but a disaster for work&quot; src=&quot;//www.opendoorcoworking.com/images/needy-cat.jpg&quot; class=&quot;blog-pic&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Try working with this guy staring you down&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working from home brings its own distractions to the table.  Cats nuzzling, dogs barking, and babies crying are just the tip of the iceberg.  Some family members may have a hard time recognizing that you’re actually working and expect you to drop everything to help them.  Sometimes, it’s just the video game or TV in the corner calling out to you.  “Play me!  It’ll only take a few minutes!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of your distractions, they’re definitely there and keeping you from doing best, but &lt;em&gt;why is a coworking space better?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, coworking spaces have their own distractions, but they are the distractions that you’d expect from an office environment and not from a house or apartment.  Your fellow coworkers are there to work and respect the fact that you are too.  At &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opendoorcoworking.com&quot;&gt;Open Door Coworking&lt;/a&gt; we utilize an instant messaging application, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slack.com&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; for our members and are firm believers in the headphone rule, or the rule that if the headphones are on then that person is not to be disturbed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;list-header&quot;&gt;2. Leave your house at home and your work at work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, one of the most difficult parts of working from home, and I speak from personal experience on this, is that it’s &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; difficult to separate your work hours from your home hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Coworking Venn Diagram&quot; src=&quot;//www.opendoorcoworking.com/images/coworking-venn.png&quot; class=&quot;blog-pic&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Based on the very scientific method of me asking people who work from coworking spaces if this is how they feel&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re at home, your mind and body know you’re at home so the tendency to act like you’re at home is there more than you might realize.  Just like the distractions, it’s pretty easy to turn on the TV to watch the news, but end up catching up on Let’s Make a Deal and The Price is Right and realize that it’s 11:00 AM and you’ve squandered a few hours of the day away that could have been better put to use doing your job, making client calls, or brainstorming.  It’s also easy to see that pile of dishes in the sink and find yourself doing chores instead of working.  Guess what, doing chores won’t pay the bills no matter how accomplished you feel after sweeping those cobwebs out of that closet in that room in the basement that is really only there because someone didn’t plan the bathroom as well as they could have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inverse of that is without the separation of home and job, you may find yourself sinking into work when you should be spending time with your family or significant other.  Not getting enough done is bad, but getting too much done at the cost of your personal relationships and family life is even worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The time you have between your home and office, going either way, acts as kind of a “buffer” between “home” you and “work” you. That’s also nice because…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;list-header&quot;&gt;3. You get to dress the part&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s right, ladies and gentlemen.  A coworking space means you &lt;s&gt;have to&lt;/s&gt; get to put on clothes for the day.  For some people, working in their pajamas/underwear is great, but unfortunately it’s looked down upon in public.  Personally, I think that a nice pair of jeans and a button front shirt or sweater makes great business casual, and I just &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; more professional when I’m not wearing a stained tee shirt and flannel pajama pants.  Sure, it sounds awesome to not have to get dressed or shower or brush your teeth or do laundry because nobody will see you for days, but if you have any sense of self worth you quickly find yourself questioning your choices in life and running for the nearest shower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of segues and other reasons to get cleaned up…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;list-header&quot;&gt;4. Grow your social network&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, I don’t mean your Facebook friends, Twitter followers, or LinkedIn connections (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/opendoorcoworking&quot;&gt;Open Door on Facebook&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/OpenDoorCowork&quot;&gt;Open Door on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/open-door-coworking/&quot;&gt;Open Door on LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;.  Sorry, had to!)  I mean actual human people.  We all need to have human contact at least every once in a while and you’re not going to meet anyone new in your basement.  According to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.deskmag.com/en/the-coworking-market-report-forecast-2014&quot;&gt;deskmag survey&lt;/a&gt;, 92% of coworkers noted an improved social circle, not to mention all of the contacts that you gain from meeting new people who might be or might know someone who is interested in your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also great to have people to bounce ideas off of.  It’s really easy to trap yourself in an echo chamber at home.  A lot of the time family and friends will either a) think that everything you do is amazing, or b) not have any idea what it is you’re trying to do.  At a coworking space, the other members are more likely to give honest feedback before you dump a lot of time and money into an idea that Aunt Gertrude thought sounded “just swell” and that would “make you one of those internet millionaires” when in reality you’re just trying to market hair ties for cat tails.  Just trust me on that one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;list-header&quot;&gt;5. Look More Professional&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we talked about looking professional a few items ago.  Well this is a little bit different.  It’s not just how you get to dress, it’s also your surroundings.  You could have the nicest tailored suit from the finest shop in town, but it doesn’t really matter if you’re holding client meetings at a dirty kitchen table or if customers have to dodge Legos to get to your office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A coworking space gives the appearance and feel of a professional environment for both you and your customers and clients.  With several amenities including a conference room for members to hold meetings, it makes working that much easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;list-header&quot;&gt;6. All of the above&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these elements combine to form a whole greater than the sum of its parts.  Working from a coworking space is &lt;em&gt;empowering&lt;/em&gt;.  You get to look professional in a professional environment while maintaining a strong work life balance in a distraction-free zone while growing your social network for a fraction of the cost of renting or buying an office outright.  You get all this and you get to keep your independence as a freelancer, entrepreneur, small business owner, or telecommuter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think that coworking might be for you, please give us a call at &lt;a href=&quot;tel:219-561-0219&quot;&gt;219-561-0219&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#106;&amp;#100;&amp;#064;&amp;#111;&amp;#112;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#100;&amp;#111;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#119;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#107;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#103;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/forms/ook9usnqsn&quot;&gt;go ahead and schedule a tour&lt;/a&gt; now and set up a day or two of trial coworking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What about those of you who have tried coworking?  Do you agree, disagree, or something else entirely?  Let me know in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2016 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/coworking/2016/01/04/6-reasons-to-leave-the-home-office-behind/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/coworking/2016/01/04/6-reasons-to-leave-the-home-office-behind/</guid>
        
        
        <category>coworking</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Technically Laporte Meetup</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Done anything cool recently that you want to show off?  Anything in the area bugging you technically?  Got an idea that you want to bounce off a few people?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us at Open Door Coworking for a roundtable discussion about technical topics, interesting finds, or anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, seeking speakers and topics for future meetups.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 07:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/events/2016/01/technically-laporte-meetup/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/events/2016/01/technically-laporte-meetup/</guid>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Laporte Tabletop Gamers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the inagural meeting, La Porte Tabletop Gamers will be getting together and, you guessed it, playing some tabletop games!  Come join the fun and bring your favorite board game along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please be sure to RSVP at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/La-Porte-Tabletop-Gamers/events/227564660/&quot;&gt;meetup.com&lt;/a&gt; because space is limited.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 07:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/events/2016/01/laporte-tabletop-gamers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/events/2016/01/laporte-tabletop-gamers/</guid>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Exactly is &#39;Coworking&#39;?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The most common response that I get when I tell people, “Hey, people, I just opened a coworking space for La Porte County!” is “That’s awesome!  Um… what’s a coworking space?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it is not entirely unexpected, it does sadden me to a point that something as amazing as coworking is such a foreign concept to the majority of the population.  An informal survey done by another coworking space owner found that roughly 10% of adults questioned had heard of a coworking space.  Of that 10%, only 3-4 people actually knew what a coworking space was or had a vague grasp of the concept.  The silver lining?  Most people wanted to know more about coworking spaces after they were told what it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what is coworking?  As the &lt;a href=&quot;/index.html&quot;&gt;front page&lt;/a&gt; of the site (copied from the Google definition) puts it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
  Coworking is the use of an office or other working environment by people who are self-employed or working for different employers, typically so as to share equipment, ideas, and knowledge.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-what-exactly-does-this-mean-and-why-is-it-even-a-thing&quot;&gt;But what exactly does this mean and why is it even a thing?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, if coworking is  sharing ideas, equipment, and knowledge while working, then a coworking space is a location to facilitate coworking.  Sounds good, right?  Right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coworking spaces come in all shapes, sizes, and directions.  Some are &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt; with a ton of funding from sponsorships and grants, while some are small and modest coming from one or two people with a vision to bring a new style of working and thinking to their community.  Open Door Coworking definitely falls into the second category with no sponsorships or outside funding. Just a guy with a dream to bring something different and wonderful to his community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal for Open Door Coworking is to give you, the people of La Porte, Michigan City, and the rest of the county, a chance to get out of your houses or coffee shops.  I want to make everything necessary for a budding entrepreneur or freelancer to succeed be within reach.  I want telecommuters to be able to separate their home lives from their work lives without having to sacrifice independence.  I want to build a community within our community of talented, smart, like-minded people together and watch the ideas form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-its-not-just-a-shared-office&quot;&gt;So, it’s not just a shared office?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Definitely not.  The entire coworking community and mentality is founded on the belief that people work better together.  Amazing things happen when you get the right mix of professionals in a room together.  A common misconception is that coworking spaces are only for one type of professional.  People assume that only technology related fields thrive in coworking spaces, but I’ve seen health professionals, accountants, authors, bloggers, and insurance companies thrive in coworking spaces.  Social and professional networks grow, productivity increases, and members are able to actually communicate with real human people.  Before I opened Open Door Coworking, my daily conversations were with my cat.  While he’s a nice guy, I think he’s a bit of a yes-man and way too agreeable with every idea I had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference between shared office space and a coworking space is that the former usually means come rent an office, use the conference room, and stay to yourself.  The latter is an invitation to join the community.  The amenities are nice, but the real value is in the people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-should-i-join-a-coworking-space-instead-of-staying-home-or-working-from-insert-go-to-workplace-here&quot;&gt;Why should I join a coworking space instead of staying home or working from [insert go-to workplace here]?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A coworking space empowers you to be able to, as a freelancer or budding entrepreneur, say “I’m heading to the office!” or to invite clients to an actual conference room that isn’t in your kitchen or the middle of a crowded bistro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A coworking space helps you become more creative by allowing you to bounce ideas off of your coworkers or tap resources that you wouldn’t be able to find elsewhere without an appointment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A coworking space takes care of the utilities, internet, and at Open Door, the coffee and water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A coworking space costs a fraction of what a traditional office would cost with more benefits to a growing business than a traditional office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A coworking space, at least Open Door Coworking, doesn’t lock you into a long term lease so if your business doesn’t do as well as you had hoped, you aren’t stuck, or, even better, if your business outgrows the coworking space, you’re free to move on to bigger, better things!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A coworking space distances you from home so those tempting televisions, video games, and beds don’t keep you from doing the work you need to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-you-waiting-for&quot;&gt;What are you waiting for?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A coworking space isn’t for everyone and I’m not here to claim that joining one will guarantee success, but if you’re like me and you find that you have a hard time working in places that aren’t offices or you want to be surrounded by other professionals, then a coworking space may be for you.  If you want to give it a try, then &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/forms/ook9usnqsn&quot;&gt;sign up for a trial day&lt;/a&gt; and see for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you think?  Did I leave any questions unanswered, did I explain it clearly, or did I just make it more confusing?  Let me know in the comments!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 07:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/coworking/2015/12/30/what-is-coworking/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/coworking/2015/12/30/what-is-coworking/</guid>
        
        
        <category>coworking</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Did I Open a Coworking Space?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most common questions I get, next to “What is a coworking space?”, is “Why open a coworking space?”  It’s definitely a fair question, and the short answer is “for the community.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please, come along and imagine yourself on my train of thought.  I’ll try to do everything that I can to keep from derailing as I tell you my story.  It all started on a warm, summer day in 1982… Wait, that’s a little &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; far back.  Okay, when I first became a professional web developer (meaning taking it from a hobby to a paying job) I immediately began looking for work in Chicago.  In my eyes, traveling to the city every day was the only option.  There weren’t a lot of web shops in the area and job postings for web developers were either grossly underpaid or non-existent.  I did a brief stint as a freelancer, but it just wasn’t right for me, so Chicago it was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I landed a job for a media group as a PHP developer and I thought it would be &lt;em&gt;GREAT&lt;/em&gt;, and it was for a while.  However, after the first few months of&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;getting up at 4:30 to get on the 5:30 train&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;spending 90 minutes on the train&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;walking the 6 blocks to the office from the station&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;working my 8 hours&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;rushing back to the station&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;90 more minutes on the train&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;drive home&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;repeat as needed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was burning out very quickly.  My boss recognized this and offered me a few days from home a week.  To me, this seemed like a great idea.  I was able to get off work at a decent time, sleep in until daylight on some days, and I didn’t have to suffer the scents of the train.  However, I noticed that I wasn’t as productive on my work-from-home days as I was in the office.  While the office had people holding trivial conversations across the hallway, it was still a more professional environment.  My home office was in my basement and separated from everything else in the house, but there were still dogs barking at the wind or the mail carrier or their shadow (all evil), kids running back and forth screaming as toddlers do, and just the inability to separate work from life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might not realize it, but when you walk past an Xbox every time you go for another cup of coffee, it’s very tempting to tell yourself “Just one round…” and end up wasting work time that you have to make up by working later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to try my work-from-home days in local coffee shops, and they were great, but there were still distractions.  People were holding conversations so loudly that I felt like I was part of them, random lonely people saw that I was sitting by myself and assumed that I needed conversation (which I was more than happy to take part in.  You can really learn a lot about this town just by listening to some of the residents’ stories), and, depending on which shop I spent the day at, there were often baristas grossly mispronouncing names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This didn’t improve my productivity and the commute was taking its toll on my well being.  I began looking for fully remote jobs and landed the perfect job for me as a web developer for a destination marketing organization.  I went back to working from home, but I had the same concentration issues and poor productivity.  I did the coffee shops, but I couldn’t get as much done as I wanted to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I was working in Chicago I made some good contacts with other web developers, so I used those contacts and asked them for recommendations.  How did they separate work and life?  Where did they go?  What did they do that kept them more focused than me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The majority of remote workers and freelancers that I knew told me about various coworking spaces that they used in the city. I considered it, but that would put me back at commuting every day and I did &lt;em&gt;NOT&lt;/em&gt; want to do that again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started looking and I found 2 within 40 miles of me.  One in the next county over to the east and the other in the next county over to the west, but none right here in La Porte County.  I decided to use my coffee shop experiences as market research and decided that this county could benefit from having a coworking space.  I’m obviously not the only telecommuter in town and I can guarantee that there are a lot more entrepreneurs and freelancers in La Porte and Michigan City than anyone might expect.  I was certain that a coworking space would be beneficial not only to me, but to the community in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a period of failed attempts to raise the money necessary to open a space, a property owner in La Porte came to the rescue.  He told me that he had a few larger offices that weren’t being used, and as a startup success himself, he would like to pay it forward and made me a deal on a PERFECT location for what I was trying to do.  Thus, Open Door Coworking was born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, the community leaders have been beyond helpful in getting the word out about the concept of coworking and the fact that there is a coworking space in La Porte County for all of the residents of the county.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can imagine yourself in the position I was in, having a hard time separating work from home life, not getting as much done as you could be, or just wanting the feeling of working from a professional environment, please don’t hesitate to schedule a &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/forms/ook9usnqsn&quot;&gt;free day of coworking or just a tour&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next time: Just what is coworking?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2015 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/coworking/2015/12/29/why-coworking/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/coworking/2015/12/29/why-coworking/</guid>
        
        
        <category>coworking</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
