<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Door Coworking</title>
    <description>Open Door Coworking is LaPorte, Indiana&#39;s first coworking space for freelancers, entrepreneurs, and telecommuters to call home. Work independently; not alone.</description>
    <link>http://www.opendoorcoworking.com/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.opendoorcoworking.com/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2015 14:37:41 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2015 14:37:41 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Open a Coworking Space?</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/slider/cowork5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Coworking Desk&quot; class=&quot;top-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most common questions I get, next to “What is a coworking space?”, is “Why open a coworking space?”  It’s definitely a fair question, and the short answer is “for the community.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please, come along and imagine yourself on my train of thought.  I’ll try to do everything that I can to keep from derailing as I tell you my story.  It all started on a warm, summer day in 1982… Wait, that’s a little &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; far back.  Okay, when I first became a professional web developer (meaning taking it from a hobby to a paying job) I immediately began looking for work in Chicago.  In my eyes, traveling to the city every day was the only option.  There weren’t a lot of web shops in the area and job postings for web developers were either grossly underpaid or non-existant.  I did a brief stint as a freelancer, but it just wasn’t right for me, so Chicago it was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I landed a job for a media group as a PHP developer and I thought it would be &lt;em&gt;GREAT&lt;/em&gt;, and it was for a while.  However, after the first few months of
- getting up at 4:30 to get on the 5:30 train
- spending 90 minutes on the train
- walking the 6 blocks to the office from the station
- working my 8 hours
- rushing back to the station
- 90 more minutes on the train
- drive home
- repeat as needed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was burning out very quickly.  My boss recognized this and offered me a few days from home a week.  To me, this seemed like a great idea.  I was able to get off work at a decent time, sleep in until daylight on some days, and I didn’t have to suffer the scents of the train.  However, I noticed that I wasn’t as productive on my work-from-home days as I was in the office.  While the office had people holding trivial conversations across the hallway, it was still a more professional environment.  My home office was in my basement and separated from everything else in the house, but there were still dogs barking at the wind or the mail carrier or their shadow (all evil), kids running back and forth screaming as toddlers do, and just the inability to separate work from life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might not realize it, but when you walk past an Xbox every time you go for another cup of coffee, it’s very tempting to tell yourself “Just one round…” and end up wasting work time that you have to make up by working later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to try my work-from-home days in local coffee shops, and they were great, but there were still distractions.  People were holding conversations so loudly that I felt like I was part of them, random lonely people saw that I was sitting by myself and assumed that I needed conversation (which I was more than happy to take part in.  You can really learn a lot about this town just by listening to some of the residents’ stories), and, depending on which shop I spent the day at, there were often baristas grossly mispronouncing names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This didn’t improve my productivity and the commute was taking its toll on my well being.  I began looking for fully remote jobs and landed the perfect job for me as a web developer for a destination marketing organization.  I went back to working from home, but I had the same concentration issues and poor productivity.  I did the coffee shops, but I couldn’t get as much done as I wanted to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I was working in Chicago I made some good contacts with other web developers, so I used those contacts and asked them for recommendations.  How did they separate work and life?  Where did they go?  What did they do that kept them more focused than me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The majority of remote workers and freelancers that I knew told me about various coworking spaces that they used in the city. I considered it, but that would put me back at commuting every day and I did &lt;em&gt;NOT&lt;/em&gt; want to do that again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started looking and I found 2 within 40 miles of me.  One in the next county over to the east and the other in the next county over to the west, but none right here in La Porte County.  I decided to use my coffee shop experiences as market research and decided that this county could benefit from having a coworking space.  I’m obviously not the only telecommuter in town and I can guarantee that there are a lot more entrepreneurs and freelancers in La Porte and Michigan City than anyone might expect.  I was certain that a coworking space would be beneficial not only to me, but to the community in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a period of failed attempts to raise the money necessary to open a space, a property owner in La Porte came to the rescue.  He told me that he had a few larger offices that weren’t being used, and as a startup success himself, he would like to pay it forward and made me a deal on a PERFECT location for what I was trying to attempt.  Thus, Open Door Coworking was born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, the community leaders have been beyond helpful in getting the word out about the concept of coworking and the fact that there is a coworking space in La Porte County for all of the residents of the county.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next time: Just what is coworking?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2015 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.opendoorcoworking.com/blog/coworking/2015/12/29/why-coworking/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.opendoorcoworking.com/blog/coworking/2015/12/29/why-coworking/</guid>
        
        
        <category>coworking</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
