<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Door Coworking</title>
    <description>Open Door Coworking is LaPorte, Indiana&#39;s first coworking space for freelancers, entrepreneurs, and telecommuters to call home. Work independently; not alone.</description>
    <link>http://www.opendoorcoworking.com/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.opendoorcoworking.com/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2015 14:06:06 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2015 14:06:06 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Open a Coworking Space?</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/slider/cowork5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Coworking Desk&quot; class=&quot;top-image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most common questions I get, next to “What is a coworking space?”, is “Why open a coworking space?”  It’s definitely a fair question, and the short answer is “for the community.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please, come along and imagine yourself on my train of thought.  I’ll try to do everything that I can to keep from derailing as I tell you my story.  It all started on a warm, summer day in 1982… Wait, that’s a little &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; far back.  Okay, when I first became a professional web developer (meaning taking it from a hobby to a paying job) I immediately began looking for work in Chicago.  In my eyes, traveling to the city every day was the only option.  There weren’t a lot of web shops in the area and job postings for web developers were either grossly underpaid or non-existant.  I did a brief stint as a freelancer, but it just wasn’t right for me, so Chicago it was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I landed a job for a media group as a PHP developer and I thought it would be &lt;em&gt;*GREAT*&lt;/em&gt;, and it was for a while.  However, the first few months consisted of
- getting up at 4:30 to get on the 5:30 train
- spending 90 minutes on the train
- walking the 6 blocks to the office from the station
- working my 8 hours
- rushing back to the station
- 90 more minutes on the train
- drive home
- repeat as needed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I was thrilled to be a out of my old job and into something that I loved doing, I was burning out very quickly.  My boss recognized this and offered me a few days from home a week.  To me, this seemed like a great idea, but I noticed that I wasn’t very productive on my work-from-home days, but I stuck with it.  I was able to get off work at a decent time&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2015 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.opendoorcoworking.com/blog/coworking/2015/12/29/why-coworking/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.opendoorcoworking.com/blog/coworking/2015/12/29/why-coworking/</guid>
        
        
        <category>coworking</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
