<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Door Coworking</title>
    <description>Open Door Coworking is LaPorte, Indiana&#39;s first coworking space for freelancers, entrepreneurs, and telecommuters to call home. Work independently; not alone.</description>
    <link>https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 17:17:46 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 17:17:46 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Technically Laporte Meetup</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Wordpress? Drupal? Joomla? What are all of these and what do they mean?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever considered building your own website, then you’ve probably looked at at least one of these names, if not all of them. What is different between them and which one is the best for you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us for a brief presentation on Content Management Systems and the differences between them followed by a period of networking and open discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/events/2016/04/technically-laporte-meetup/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/events/2016/04/technically-laporte-meetup/</guid>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Laporte Tabletop Gamers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;La Porte Tabletop Gamers will be getting together and, you guessed it, playing some tabletop games!  Come join the fun and bring your favorite board game along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please be sure to RSVP at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/La-Porte-Tabletop-Gamers/events/228617237/&quot;&gt;meetup.com&lt;/a&gt; because space is limited.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/events/2016/04/laporte-tabletop-gamers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/events/2016/04/laporte-tabletop-gamers/</guid>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Open Door Coworking Grand Opening</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Join Open Door Coworking for a ribbon cutting and grand opening on Wednesday, April 20 at 4:30 p.m. The event will take place at 1705 State Street in La Porte and will be administered by the Greater La Porte Chamber of Commerce. Come and tour the facility while learning what coworking is all about. The ribbon cutting will take place at 5:15 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open Door Coworking lets you get your business out of your home and into your very own affordable, professional, all-inclusive workspace. Whether you’re starting a business, have an established business, or are working remotely for a company, you work better when you are able to concentrate on doing business. A coworking space helps you separate your home life from your work life, increasing productivity and reducing “bad” distractions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about Open Door Coworking, visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.opendoorcoworking.com&quot;&gt;opendoorcoworking.com&lt;/a&gt; or call 219.561.0219. For more information about the Greater La Porte Chamber of Commerce, or to become a member, visit www.lpchamber.com or call 219.362.3178.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/events/2016/04/open-door-coworking-grand-opening/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/events/2016/04/open-door-coworking-grand-opening/</guid>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Coworking Space Versus Incubator Problem</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-in-a-name&quot;&gt;What’s in a name?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The coworking space manager/owner community is pretty knowledgeable about how to correctly term various things in our vertical that have to do with coworking spaces.  We are not community managers, we’re community &lt;em&gt;facilitators&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;tummlers&lt;/em&gt; meaning that we don’t want to manage the community; we want to make the space available for the community to thrive.  We also don’t ask for people to &lt;em&gt;sign up&lt;/em&gt; for our coworking spaces.  We offer them the chance to &lt;em&gt;join&lt;/em&gt; or become a part of the community.  Signing up sounds too much like enlisting, but joining or becoming a member sounds much more welcoming.  Whether conscious or not, these terms make a difference when trying to promote our spaces and propose value to potential members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One issue that comes up now and again, aside from the “coworking” v. “co-working” debate (hint: it’s “coworking” and anyone who tells you otherwise just needs to be informed) is the “coworking space” versus “tech/startup incubator” problem.  To many who aren’t familiar with the concept of either, the terms are interchangable.  However, there is a huge difference between a coworking space and an incubator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-the-difference-if-any&quot;&gt;What is the difference, if any?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;an-incubator-wants-your-business--a-coworking-space-would-rather-have-your-company&quot;&gt;An incubator wants your business.  A coworking space would rather have your company&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As crazy as that sounds, the normal operating model for an incubator is to allow tech startups and the like to work from their facilities in return for a cut of the business.  This is often measured in equity, ownership, a portion of profits, or a seat on the board.  While this isn’t always the case, it is pretty common among incubators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what do I mean by “a coworking space would rather have your company”?  Simply put, coworking spaces are in place for the purpose of creating a collaborative community, or building a place for you to work independently together.  Less simply put, those of us who open coworking spaces generally see a niche in the community that’s somewhere between “idea in my kitchen” and “ready for my own office building.”  We realize that not everyone working out of a coffee shop is trying to startup a business.  We want to be open to anyone who is need of professional office space at a low cost and without a long-term commitment.  We take our titles as facilitators and tummlers seriously and we want to bring people together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;who-uses-incubators&quot;&gt;Who uses incubators?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my experience, people who prefer incubators are often the startups who are seeking a place to work and handle their day-to-day while building their branding.  Incubators are often funded by equity, so if a startup within an incubator gets that ever-so-sought-after seed money from a VC, the incubator takes their chunk of the pie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;who-uses-coworking-spaces&quot;&gt;Who uses coworking spaces?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coworking spaces are not aligned with any certain industry.  You’ll find web developers, accountants, insurance sales, entrepreneurs, IT consultants, authors, and any number of other professionals in a coworking space.  Solopreneurs to remote workers, single person businesses to some of the largest companies in the world, they all use coworking spaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;are-you-getting-to-the-difference-anytime-soon&quot;&gt;Are you getting to the difference anytime soon?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes.  Yes I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coworking spaces are much less structured than incubators in a good way.  You pay your membership, you work when you want and where you want within the terms of your membership, you use the facilities as you need to, and you grow your community and social circles.  Incubators often have set hours, where coworking spaces are usually more flexible, most of the time with 24 hour access 7 days a week for members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incubators are focused on the industry.  Coworking spaces are focused on the culture.  In an incubator you may work alongside other entrepreneurs, but you probably won’t be considered their coworker, nor will you get the benefits of the expanded social circles and networks that having this diverse collection of coworkers might bring you.  A coworking space will bring you the chance to work alongside other people and organizations.  You’ll have access to peer-to-peer mentorship to and from your new professional network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-biased-verdict&quot;&gt;The biased verdict?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at the title of this site.  I founded a coworking space so I’m going to be completely transparent in my bias.  I prefer the coworking space, but I’m also a remote web developer not looking for VCs or seed money.  Either a coworking space or an incubator is going to be beneficial to a startup or entrepreneur, but often one will be more &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt; than the other.  A coworking space builds the community within.  It’s empowering to the small businesses to have an office to bring clients to.  It looks more professional to have a conference room than a kitchen table.  It’s more welcoming to a prospective customer to walk into a coworking space’s entryway than it is to bring them in through the garage and past the laundry room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the majority of people in this area who are looking for professional office space with no long-term leases and all professional amenities included, a coworking space is going to be a better choice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 13:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/coworking/2016/03/27/coworking-v-incubation/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/coworking/2016/03/27/coworking-v-incubation/</guid>
        
        
        <category>coworking</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Problem With Building A Community</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A wise man once told me, “What do you think you’re doing opening a coworking space without first building a community?”  Everything I read about opening a space told me that I should be working on cultivating a community before trying to create a coworking space, but I went rogue and started the company first and then got the community going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why did I go about it this way?  Well, it’s no secret that La Porte and Michigan City are in a bit of a void when it come to getting the word out about something new, and I actually tried building the community, but I had a hard time for several reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The community doesn’t have as many events as a bigger city&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is a significant hole in my target demographic, millennials&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There aren’t a lot of places to hold meetups&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People don’t know about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com&quot;&gt;Meetup.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did some research, made some calls, and found that there wasn’t a lot to unite like-minded individuals.  There also weren’t an abundance of locations to hold meetups in the county.  The libraries had some space available, but with limited hours and space it was not the best option.  There are plenty of bars and restaurants, but I didn’t want people to feel obligated to have to spend money to come and join in the conversations.  I wanted to build a community, but there was nothing available to use as a clubhouse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Against every bit of advice I got, I decided to open a space and build the clubhouse before the club.  In my ignorance, I thought that I heard a voice from the field saying “If you build it; they will come.”  As with any business, this was not the case.  I had to build a community, and let me tell you, it is &lt;em&gt;HARD&lt;/em&gt; in an area like La Porte and Michigan City.  There are only so many media outlets and it’s difficult to tell which medium is going to reach the most appropriate audience so I tried the shotgun method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I advertised on Facebook and saw a very, very poor return on investment.  I sent press releases to every media outlet and got a few page views, but most saw the press releases as too much like an advertisement.  Guilty as charged.  I was trying to get free advertisement, but I was also trying to get the word out about a completely new concept to the area.  I did manage to get the attention of one newspaper, but the interest that it created was negligible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More recently, I had 15 minutes of fame on a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wimsradio.com&quot;&gt;local AM radio station&lt;/a&gt; which sounds a lot less awesome than it really was.  The morning host, Ric Federighi, made the interview flow and kept it interesting instead of me droning on about how great I think coworking is and why everyone should do it.  It was an amazing experience, but after checking the Google Analytics of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opendoorcoworking.com&quot;&gt;opendoorcoworking.com&lt;/a&gt; I saw that the impact was once again not there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here’s my problem.  I have a space and I have the support of many community leaders who all think that a coworking space is going to be great for the area, but what I don’t have is a strong method to get the word out about the space and its benefits. So, has anyone had experience building a community in a small city with only a few methods of mass communication?  If so, let me know in the comments or on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/jddoesdev&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/opendoorcoworking&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/coworking/2016/02/04/building-community/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/coworking/2016/02/04/building-community/</guid>
        
        
        <category>coworking</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Laporte Tabletop Gamers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;La Porte Tabletop Gamers will be getting together and, you guessed it, playing some tabletop games!  Come join the fun and bring your favorite board game along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please be sure to RSVP at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/La-Porte-Tabletop-Gamers/events/228617237/&quot;&gt;meetup.com&lt;/a&gt; because space is limited.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 07:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/events/2016/02/laporte-tabletop-gamers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/events/2016/02/laporte-tabletop-gamers/</guid>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Technically Laporte Blog Workshop</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Thinking about starting your own blog? Got something you want to say to the world, but aren’t sure how to get started? Interested in learning how blogs work and best practices? Join J.D. Flynn and Technically La Porte for a presentation on different platforms for blogging and some tips and tricks to help get your blog found once you’re set up!  Please RSVP at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Technically-LaPorte/events/228523064/&quot;&gt;the Technically La Porte Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also looking for presenters and sponsors for future meetups.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 07:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/events/2016/02/technically-laporte-blog-workshop/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/events/2016/02/technically-laporte-blog-workshop/</guid>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Drupal Global Sprint Weekend Day 2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us on Saturday, January 30 and Sunday, January 31 at Open Door Coworking Space in Laporte for the Drupal Global Sprint Weekend!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sprint will focus on Drupal 8 issues, and porting modules to Drupal 8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not up for coding? Some examples of other activities you can do at the sprint include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Writing docs for core or contributed modules&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Working on presentations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Testing or reviewing patches for core or contributed modules&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Anything else that helps make Drupal awesome!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will start at 9:00am and continue until around 6pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about Global Sprint Weekend and RSVP on &lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.drupal.org/node/488988&quot;&gt;groups.drupal.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 07:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/events/2016/01/drupal-global-sprint-weekend-day-2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/events/2016/01/drupal-global-sprint-weekend-day-2/</guid>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How To Remain Productive While Working From Home</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So you’ve decided that working from home is the best option for you.  That’s awesome!  I tried it for a while, but I found that I need some human contact and to get out of the house in order to do the best work that I can.  In fact, I opened a business because of it.  However, I did pick up a few pointers in my time working from my basement that helped me work better and kept me on track AKA employed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;start-the-day-off-right&quot;&gt;Start the day off right&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;No, I don’t mean have a balanced breakfast, although that is important, I mean treat your home office like an office.  If you’re going to work, then act like it.  Wake up, take a shower, get dressed, and do something to separate your work from your home-life.  Some people do well with a walk or run, some people can drive around the block and get that distance.  Personally, I liked to watch the news and walk around the block to get the working juices flowing.  It also really, really helps to dress the part.  There’s something that flips in my brain when I get out of my comic book pajama pants and into something resembling professional attire.  I’m not saying that you should suit up every morning, but a nice pair of jeans and a sweater or button-front shirt will do wonders for how you approach the rest of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;make-sure-your-home-life-respects-your-work-life&quot;&gt;Make sure your home life respects your work life&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This is one of the hardest possible things to do while working from home, especially if you live with your significant other or have kids.  Working from home requires that you put up a wall of separation between home and work.  If the people you live with aren’t prepared, then you need to have a discussion.  Whether you’re working for a distributed office somewhere else in the country or working for yourself as a freelancer or entrepreneur, if the people you cohabitate with do not respect that you’re working and not just hanging out then they are going to be more likely to distract you without thinking twice.
It’s easy for people to assume that working from home means you’re only going to be “kinda” working and be at their beck and call when they need you.  &lt;em&gt;DON’T LET THEM THINK THAT!&lt;/em&gt;  You are getting paid to work or working towards getting paid.  Close your door, put on some headphones, and request that they only contact you through email or slack.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;make-sure-you-can-separate-work-from-home&quot;&gt;Make sure &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; can separate work from home&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It’s easy to take a break that is supposed to last the time it takes you to get a cup of coffee and head back to your office and find yourself distracted by some dishes that need washing, laundry that needs folded, a TV that needs watched, or a conversation that someone tries to start.  DO NOT FALL INTO THIS PIT!  If you were working from an office or coworking space then those chores would be waiting for you when you got off.  Let them wait until you get off.  You have your time to work and your time for chores.  Don’t mix them.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;set-rules-for-your-housemates-and-yourself&quot;&gt;Set rules for your housemates AND yourself&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There are literally TONS of apps and tools out there that are designed to make you more productive.  One of the best that I’ve found is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/productivity-101-a-primer-to-the-pomodoro-technique-1598992730&quot;&gt;Pomodoro timer&lt;/a&gt;.  Basically, you set a 25 minute timer and work your butt off during that 25 minutes.  Focus only on your task at hand and work, work, work!  Take a 5 minute break to rest your eyes, check your email, look at your phone, etc. and then set another 25 minute timer and GO!  Repeat this 4 times, then take a 15 minute break.  Eight cycles of this and it’s time for lunch!
Some rules to consider for those around you:&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Headphone Rule - If your headphones are on, you are not available.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Door Rule - If the door is closed, it had better be something extremely important for it to be opened&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The “You know I’m Working” Rule - If someone knows that you’re working, they need to let you work&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;get-out-of-the-house&quot;&gt;Get out of the house&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If your housemates, spouses, family, or cat still can’t grasp that you need to work while you’re at home, then maybe it’s time to consider another option.  Check out local coffee shops, libraries, bookstores, or coworking spaces.  I know how awesome working remotely or working for yourself sounds, but taking that plunge
These sound a bit harsh, but if your day is full of distractions and you still need to put in 8 hours, then one of two things are going to happen:  Either you’re going to end up working until 9 PM every night catching up on work you missed because of distractions OR your Fridays are going to be very, very long.  There is a third option to that as well if you work remotely… your boss catches on that you’re not working as well as you should be and you either get pulled back to the office or, worse, fired.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important thing is that you make sure you’re really ready to work from home.  It sounds great and the stories make it seem like anyone who goes out on their own to make their fortune will succeed, but the reality is that there are a lot of people who have a hard time adjusting to working from home and need that office space mentality, not to be confused with an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0151804/&quot;&gt;Office Space Mentality&lt;/a&gt;.  Don’t see having a hard time adjusting as failure.  See it as an opportunity to learn what you can do better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully my tips help you out a bit.  Do you have any of your own?  Let me know in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/productivity/2016/01/17/stay-productive-working-from-home/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/productivity/2016/01/17/stay-productive-working-from-home/</guid>
        
        
        <category>productivity</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>6 Reasons to Leave the Home Office Behind</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I know what you’re thinking… “My home office is just fine.  There’s no reason that I should join a coworking space,” and you may be right, but imagine for a second what life might be outside of the house.  Really reflect on your current situation and ask yourself if you’re really as productive as you could be while working in your underwear 50 paces from your bed.  Having a hard time picturing it?  No problem!  That’s what this post is all about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;list-header&quot;&gt; 1. Distractions &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Distractions ruin productivity, and you and I both know that in the age we live in, disctractions are everywhere.  Your phone beeps, your watch buzzes, your computer dings, and sometimes they all happen at the same time.  These are all part of the cost of being connected, and are sometimes unavoidable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;float-right&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;He&#39;s cute, but a disaster for work&quot; src=&quot;//www.opendoorcoworking.com/images/needy-cat.jpg&quot; class=&quot;blog-pic&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Try working with this guy staring you down&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working from home brings its own distractions to the table.  Cats nuzzling, dogs barking, and babies crying are just the tip of the iceberg.  Some family members may have a hard time recognizing that you’re actually working and expect you to drop everything to help them.  Sometimes, it’s just the video game or TV in the corner calling out to you.  “Play me!  It’ll only take a few minutes!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of your distractions, they’re definitely there and keeping you from doing best, but &lt;em&gt;why is a coworking space better?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, coworking spaces have their own distractions, but they are the distractions that you’d expect from an office environment and not from a house or apartment.  Your fellow coworkers are there to work and respect the fact that you are too.  At &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opendoorcoworking.com&quot;&gt;Open Door Coworking&lt;/a&gt; we utilize an instant messaging application, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slack.com&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; for our members and are firm believers in the headphone rule, or the rule that if the headphones are on then that person is not to be disturbed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;list-header&quot;&gt;2. Leave your house at home and your work at work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, one of the most difficult parts of working from home, and I speak from personal experience on this, is that it’s &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; difficult to separate your work hours from your home hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Coworking Venn Diagram&quot; src=&quot;//www.opendoorcoworking.com/images/coworking-venn.png&quot; class=&quot;blog-pic&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Based on the very scientific method of me asking people who work from coworking spaces if this is how they feel&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re at home, your mind and body know you’re at home so the tendency to act like you’re at home is there more than you might realize.  Just like the distractions, it’s pretty easy to turn on the TV to watch the news, but end up catching up on Let’s Make a Deal and The Price is Right and realize that it’s 11:00 AM and you’ve squandered a few hours of the day away that could have been better put to use doing your job, making client calls, or brainstorming.  It’s also easy to see that pile of dishes in the sink and find yourself doing chores instead of working.  Guess what, doing chores won’t pay the bills no matter how accomplished you feel after sweeping those cobwebs out of that closet in that room in the basement that is really only there because someone didn’t plan the bathroom as well as they could have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inverse of that is without the separation of home and job, you may find yourself sinking into work when you should be spending time with your family or significant other.  Not getting enough done is bad, but getting too much done at the cost of your personal relationships and family life is even worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The time you have between your home and office, going either way, acts as kind of a “buffer” between “home” you and “work” you. That’s also nice because…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;list-header&quot;&gt;3. You get to dress the part&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s right, ladies and gentlemen.  A coworking space means you &lt;s&gt;have to&lt;/s&gt; get to put on clothes for the day.  For some people, working in their pajamas/underwear is great, but unfortunately it’s looked down upon in public.  Personally, I think that a nice pair of jeans and a button front shirt or sweater makes great business casual, and I just &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; more professional when I’m not wearing a stained tee shirt and flannel pajama pants.  Sure, it sounds awesome to not have to get dressed or shower or brush your teeth or do laundry because nobody will see you for days, but if you have any sense of self worth you quickly find yourself questioning your choices in life and running for the nearest shower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of segues and other reasons to get cleaned up…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;list-header&quot;&gt;4. Grow your social network&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, I don’t mean your Facebook friends, Twitter followers, or LinkedIn connections (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/opendoorcoworking&quot;&gt;Open Door on Facebook&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/OpenDoorCowork&quot;&gt;Open Door on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/open-door-coworking/&quot;&gt;Open Door on LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;.  Sorry, had to!)  I mean actual human people.  We all need to have human contact at least every once in a while and you’re not going to meet anyone new in your basement.  According to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.deskmag.com/en/the-coworking-market-report-forecast-2014&quot;&gt;deskmag survey&lt;/a&gt;, 92% of coworkers noted an improved social circle, not to mention all of the contacts that you gain from meeting new people who might be or might know someone who is interested in your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also great to have people to bounce ideas off of.  It’s really easy to trap yourself in an echo chamber at home.  A lot of the time family and friends will either a) think that everything you do is amazing, or b) not have any idea what it is you’re trying to do.  At a coworking space, the other members are more likely to give honest feedback before you dump a lot of time and money into an idea that Aunt Gertrude thought sounded “just swell” and that would “make you one of those internet millionaires” when in reality you’re just trying to market hair ties for cat tails.  Just trust me on that one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;list-header&quot;&gt;5. Look More Professional&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we talked about looking professional a few items ago.  Well this is a little bit different.  It’s not just how you get to dress, it’s also your surroundings.  You could have the nicest tailored suit from the finest shop in town, but it doesn’t really matter if you’re holding client meetings at a dirty kitchen table or if customers have to dodge Legos to get to your office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A coworking space gives the appearance and feel of a professional environment for both you and your customers and clients.  With several amenities including a conference room for members to hold meetings, it makes working that much easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;list-header&quot;&gt;6. All of the above&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these elements combine to form a whole greater than the sum of its parts.  Working from a coworking space is &lt;em&gt;empowering&lt;/em&gt;.  You get to look professional in a professional environment while maintaining a strong work life balance in a distraction-free zone while growing your social network for a fraction of the cost of renting or buying an office outright.  You get all this and you get to keep your independence as a freelancer, entrepreneur, small business owner, or telecommuter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think that coworking might be for you, please give us a call at &lt;a href=&quot;tel:219-561-0219&quot;&gt;219-561-0219&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#106;&amp;#100;&amp;#064;&amp;#111;&amp;#112;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#100;&amp;#111;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#119;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#107;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#103;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/forms/ook9usnqsn&quot;&gt;go ahead and schedule a tour&lt;/a&gt; now and set up a day or two of trial coworking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What about those of you who have tried coworking?  Do you agree, disagree, or something else entirely?  Let me know in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2016 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/coworking/2016/01/04/6-reasons-to-leave-the-home-office-behind/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/coworking/2016/01/04/6-reasons-to-leave-the-home-office-behind/</guid>
        
        
        <category>coworking</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
