<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Door Coworking</title>
    <description>Open Door Coworking is LaPorte, Indiana&#39;s first coworking space for freelancers, entrepreneurs, and telecommuters to call home. Work independently; not alone.</description>
    <link>https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 16:09:48 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 16:09:48 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>La Porte County Freelancer Entrepreneur Network</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’ve grown big enough that I think we can all benefit from meeting a few new people!  Join us at Open Door Coworking for some snacks, drinks, and networking.  The ticket price of $7.50 is to help offset the cost of food and drink until we find more sponsors.  Open Door Coworking members are free!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please RSVP at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/La-Porte-County-Entrepreneur-and-Freelancer-Network/events/230124193/&quot;&gt;the La Porte County Entrepreneur and Freelancer Network Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/events/2016/06/la-porte-county-freelancer-entrepreneur-network/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/events/2016/06/la-porte-county-freelancer-entrepreneur-network/</guid>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Technically Laporte Meetup</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Topic TBD.  If you’ve got something you’d like to talk about or present on, let me know at &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#106;&amp;#100;&amp;#064;&amp;#111;&amp;#112;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#100;&amp;#111;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#119;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#107;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#103;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;&amp;#106;&amp;#100;&amp;#064;&amp;#111;&amp;#112;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#100;&amp;#111;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#119;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#107;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#103;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&lt;/a&gt;. Please RSVP at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/Technically-LaPorte/events/231722466/&quot;&gt;the Technically La Porte Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also looking for presenters and sponsors for future meetups.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/events/2016/06/technically-laporte-meetup/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/events/2016/06/technically-laporte-meetup/</guid>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Laporte Tabletop Gamers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;La Porte Tabletop Gamers will be getting together and, you guessed it, playing some tabletop games!  Come join the fun and bring your favorite board game along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please be sure to RSVP at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/La-Porte-Tabletop-Gamers/events/231340344/&quot;&gt;meetup.com&lt;/a&gt; because space is limited.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/events/2016/06/laporte-tabletop-gamers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/events/2016/06/laporte-tabletop-gamers/</guid>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Power of a Member</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When you think about the word ‘membership’ it’s easy to picture an exclusive club or a fashionable jacket for only members, but for coworking space managers and owners, it is holds a completely different meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To us, our members are our reason for being.  Our members are evidence that we’re doing something beneficial.  Our members are people who have chosen to work side by side with us.  Our members are our greatest assets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-power-of-a-member-is-to-inspire&quot;&gt;The Power Of A Member is to Inspire&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first opened Open Door Coworking, it took me several months before I got my first bite.  It was a rough several months of me walking into the space every day, making my coffee, sitting at my desk in a big, empty office, and working through the day before attending events or get-togethers that might spark some interest in someone to come join up.  I had set a hard deadline for myself that if I didn’t have a member by March 1, 2016, I was going to close the doors and consider it a failed endeavor.  The night of Valentine’s Day I got a call on my work line at about 7:00 PM.  Thinking it was another telemarketer or other spammy industry, I let it go to voicemail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I listened to the voicemail it was an actual person from my actual area interested in actual office space and to become a member of my actual coworking space.  The prospect of having a member was enough to both thrill me and terrify me.  He wanted to meet as soon as possible and he was interested in my private office space.  After a few brief phone conversations, he came in, checked it out, and was ready to sign on.  The only problem was that I had never been there before.  It seemed to me that I would never find a member so I never prepared myself.  Thankfully, he was patient with me while I worked out the kinks in my onboarding process, and he continues to renew his membership monthly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it wasn’t for him, Open Door Coworking would have been shut and locked by now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-power-of-a-member-is-to-challenge&quot;&gt;The Power Of A Member is to Challenge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two members does not a coworking space make.  I elected to work at a reserved desk in the open coworking area from the time I opened up.  The benefits of this were twofold, prospective members could see what a desk in use looks like, and I would be able to keep myself in great company once I got a few more butts in the seats.  It was several weeks again before I got my second member.  He found me through a Facebook post promoting a custom tee shirt I bought a local shop and decided that he wanted to check it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you meet with a prospective member, it’s a sort of interview process.  What do you do?  Where did you hear about Open Door?  What are your needs?  Et cetera.  But, the interview goes both ways.  I’m not just asking someone to join a coworking space.  I’m asking them to join me.  I’m asking them to consider working next to me.  I’m asking them to accept me as a coworker.  Sometimes, there are unavoidable personality conflicts, but more often than not, I find that I’m challenged to be a better person to make that person want to sit next to me many times a week and work with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-power-of-a-member-is-to&quot;&gt;The Power Of A Member is to…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The list can go on forever.  Without the members of coworking spaces, the facilitators and owners are doing nothing more than sitting in large, empty spaces wishing they had someone to talk to.  Without the members, the community wouldn’t thrive and we would just be peddling cheap office space like a landlord and not trying to build relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you, to all my members, current and future.  Without you, I wouldn’t be here.  You all make this endeavor worth attempting and keep me going.  Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/coworking/2016/05/06/power-of-member/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/coworking/2016/05/06/power-of-member/</guid>
        
        
        <category>coworking</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Technically Laporte Meetup</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Wordpress? Drupal? Joomla? What are all of these and what do they mean?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever considered building your own website, then you’ve probably looked at at least one of these names, if not all of them. What is different between them and which one is the best for you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us for a brief presentation on Content Management Systems and the differences between them followed by a period of networking and open discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/events/2016/04/technically-laporte-meetup/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/events/2016/04/technically-laporte-meetup/</guid>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Laporte Tabletop Gamers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;La Porte Tabletop Gamers will be getting together and, you guessed it, playing some tabletop games!  Come join the fun and bring your favorite board game along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please be sure to RSVP at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/La-Porte-Tabletop-Gamers/events/228617237/&quot;&gt;meetup.com&lt;/a&gt; because space is limited.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/events/2016/04/laporte-tabletop-gamers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/events/2016/04/laporte-tabletop-gamers/</guid>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Open Door Coworking Grand Opening</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Join Open Door Coworking for a ribbon cutting and grand opening on Wednesday, April 20 at 4:30 p.m. The event will take place at 1705 State Street in La Porte and will be administered by the Greater La Porte Chamber of Commerce. Come and tour the facility while learning what coworking is all about. The ribbon cutting will take place at 5:15 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open Door Coworking lets you get your business out of your home and into your very own affordable, professional, all-inclusive workspace. Whether you’re starting a business, have an established business, or are working remotely for a company, you work better when you are able to concentrate on doing business. A coworking space helps you separate your home life from your work life, increasing productivity and reducing “bad” distractions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about Open Door Coworking, visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.opendoorcoworking.com&quot;&gt;opendoorcoworking.com&lt;/a&gt; or call 219.561.0219. For more information about the Greater La Porte Chamber of Commerce, or to become a member, visit www.lpchamber.com or call 219.362.3178.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/events/2016/04/open-door-coworking-grand-opening/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/events/2016/04/open-door-coworking-grand-opening/</guid>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Coworking Space Versus Incubator Problem</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-in-a-name&quot;&gt;What’s in a name?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The coworking space manager/owner community is pretty knowledgeable about how to correctly term various things in our vertical that have to do with coworking spaces.  We are not community managers, we’re community &lt;em&gt;facilitators&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;tummlers&lt;/em&gt; meaning that we don’t want to manage the community; we want to make the space available for the community to thrive.  We also don’t ask for people to &lt;em&gt;sign up&lt;/em&gt; for our coworking spaces.  We offer them the chance to &lt;em&gt;join&lt;/em&gt; or become a part of the community.  Signing up sounds too much like enlisting, but joining or becoming a member sounds much more welcoming.  Whether conscious or not, these terms make a difference when trying to promote our spaces and propose value to potential members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One issue that comes up now and again, aside from the “coworking” v. “co-working” debate (hint: it’s “coworking” and anyone who tells you otherwise just needs to be informed) is the “coworking space” versus “tech/startup incubator” problem.  To many who aren’t familiar with the concept of either, the terms are interchangable.  However, there is a huge difference between a coworking space and an incubator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-the-difference-if-any&quot;&gt;What is the difference, if any?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;an-incubator-wants-your-business--a-coworking-space-would-rather-have-your-company&quot;&gt;An incubator wants your business.  A coworking space would rather have your company&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As crazy as that sounds, the normal operating model for an incubator is to allow tech startups and the like to work from their facilities in return for a cut of the business.  This is often measured in equity, ownership, a portion of profits, or a seat on the board.  While this isn’t always the case, it is pretty common among incubators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what do I mean by “a coworking space would rather have your company”?  Simply put, coworking spaces are in place for the purpose of creating a collaborative community, or building a place for you to work independently together.  Less simply put, those of us who open coworking spaces generally see a niche in the community that’s somewhere between “idea in my kitchen” and “ready for my own office building.”  We realize that not everyone working out of a coffee shop is trying to startup a business.  We want to be open to anyone who is need of professional office space at a low cost and without a long-term commitment.  We take our titles as facilitators and tummlers seriously and we want to bring people together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;who-uses-incubators&quot;&gt;Who uses incubators?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my experience, people who prefer incubators are often the startups who are seeking a place to work and handle their day-to-day while building their branding.  Incubators are often funded by equity, so if a startup within an incubator gets that ever-so-sought-after seed money from a VC, the incubator takes their chunk of the pie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;who-uses-coworking-spaces&quot;&gt;Who uses coworking spaces?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coworking spaces are not aligned with any certain industry.  You’ll find web developers, accountants, insurance sales, entrepreneurs, IT consultants, authors, and any number of other professionals in a coworking space.  Solopreneurs to remote workers, single person businesses to some of the largest companies in the world, they all use coworking spaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;are-you-getting-to-the-difference-anytime-soon&quot;&gt;Are you getting to the difference anytime soon?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes.  Yes I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coworking spaces are much less structured than incubators in a good way.  You pay your membership, you work when you want and where you want within the terms of your membership, you use the facilities as you need to, and you grow your community and social circles.  Incubators often have set hours, where coworking spaces are usually more flexible, most of the time with 24 hour access 7 days a week for members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incubators are focused on the industry.  Coworking spaces are focused on the culture.  In an incubator you may work alongside other entrepreneurs, but you probably won’t be considered their coworker, nor will you get the benefits of the expanded social circles and networks that having this diverse collection of coworkers might bring you.  A coworking space will bring you the chance to work alongside other people and organizations.  You’ll have access to peer-to-peer mentorship to and from your new professional network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-biased-verdict&quot;&gt;The biased verdict?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at the title of this site.  I founded a coworking space so I’m going to be completely transparent in my bias.  I prefer the coworking space, but I’m also a remote web developer not looking for VCs or seed money.  Either a coworking space or an incubator is going to be beneficial to a startup or entrepreneur, but often one will be more &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt; than the other.  A coworking space builds the community within.  It’s empowering to the small businesses to have an office to bring clients to.  It looks more professional to have a conference room than a kitchen table.  It’s more welcoming to a prospective customer to walk into a coworking space’s entryway than it is to bring them in through the garage and past the laundry room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the majority of people in this area who are looking for professional office space with no long-term leases and all professional amenities included, a coworking space is going to be a better choice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 13:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/coworking/2016/03/27/coworking-v-incubation/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/coworking/2016/03/27/coworking-v-incubation/</guid>
        
        
        <category>coworking</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Problem With Building A Community</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A wise man once told me, “What do you think you’re doing opening a coworking space without first building a community?”  Everything I read about opening a space told me that I should be working on cultivating a community before trying to create a coworking space, but I went rogue and started the company first and then got the community going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why did I go about it this way?  Well, it’s no secret that La Porte and Michigan City are in a bit of a void when it come to getting the word out about something new, and I actually tried building the community, but I had a hard time for several reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The community doesn’t have as many events as a bigger city&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is a significant hole in my target demographic, millennials&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There aren’t a lot of places to hold meetups&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People don’t know about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com&quot;&gt;Meetup.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did some research, made some calls, and found that there wasn’t a lot to unite like-minded individuals.  There also weren’t an abundance of locations to hold meetups in the county.  The libraries had some space available, but with limited hours and space it was not the best option.  There are plenty of bars and restaurants, but I didn’t want people to feel obligated to have to spend money to come and join in the conversations.  I wanted to build a community, but there was nothing available to use as a clubhouse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Against every bit of advice I got, I decided to open a space and build the clubhouse before the club.  In my ignorance, I thought that I heard a voice from the field saying “If you build it; they will come.”  As with any business, this was not the case.  I had to build a community, and let me tell you, it is &lt;em&gt;HARD&lt;/em&gt; in an area like La Porte and Michigan City.  There are only so many media outlets and it’s difficult to tell which medium is going to reach the most appropriate audience so I tried the shotgun method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I advertised on Facebook and saw a very, very poor return on investment.  I sent press releases to every media outlet and got a few page views, but most saw the press releases as too much like an advertisement.  Guilty as charged.  I was trying to get free advertisement, but I was also trying to get the word out about a completely new concept to the area.  I did manage to get the attention of one newspaper, but the interest that it created was negligible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More recently, I had 15 minutes of fame on a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wimsradio.com&quot;&gt;local AM radio station&lt;/a&gt; which sounds a lot less awesome than it really was.  The morning host, Ric Federighi, made the interview flow and kept it interesting instead of me droning on about how great I think coworking is and why everyone should do it.  It was an amazing experience, but after checking the Google Analytics of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opendoorcoworking.com&quot;&gt;opendoorcoworking.com&lt;/a&gt; I saw that the impact was once again not there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here’s my problem.  I have a space and I have the support of many community leaders who all think that a coworking space is going to be great for the area, but what I don’t have is a strong method to get the word out about the space and its benefits. So, has anyone had experience building a community in a small city with only a few methods of mass communication?  If so, let me know in the comments or on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/jddoesdev&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/opendoorcoworking&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/coworking/2016/02/04/building-community/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/coworking/2016/02/04/building-community/</guid>
        
        
        <category>coworking</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Laporte Tabletop Gamers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;La Porte Tabletop Gamers will be getting together and, you guessed it, playing some tabletop games!  Come join the fun and bring your favorite board game along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please be sure to RSVP at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/La-Porte-Tabletop-Gamers/events/228617237/&quot;&gt;meetup.com&lt;/a&gt; because space is limited.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 07:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/events/2016/02/laporte-tabletop-gamers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.opendoorcoworking.com/posts/events/2016/02/laporte-tabletop-gamers/</guid>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
